PROFESSOR: All right.
How are we going to use the heuristic?
Well, the first thing that occurs you
is, well, I have this arrow, in some
sense, that tells me whether or
not I'm close to the goal.
Why don't we just follow
the heuristic?
And you can.
That's Greedy Search.
And as you might imagine from the name,
it's not a perfect solution.
Let's figure out what it looks like.
In Greedy Search, you
look at your map.
So for example, let's say
we're at Arad again.
So we start here.
And we're trying to get to Bucharest.
And we're going to follow the
heuristic in some way.
Now, it's not going to
be hill climbing.
It's not going to be a local search.
It's going to still be a fringe.
It's just the things that come out of
the fringe will be prioritized, based
on whether or not they seem
to be close to the goal.
And so let's look at this
map for a second.
So we can understand the example.
All right.
The actual shortest path is
what I call the low road,
through Rimnicu Vilcea.
The high road, through
Fagaras, is longer.
Depth First Search would like it
because it has fewer steps.
But Uniform Cost would do the right
thing and return the low road.
Because the sum of the
path cost is lower.
OK.
So remember that.
The one through Fagaras is longer.
And it makes more progress, quickly.
Fagaras itself is closer to Bucharest.
But it's the wrong answer.
So Greedy Search, you expand the
node that seems to be closest.
So let's say you were at Arad.
And that has distance 366, according
to our heuristic.
We expand it.
And onto our fringe go the three
places you can get to in
one step, from Arad.
And you can see here that Sibiu, which
in fact is the right direction to
head, is closest.
Now, all three are on our Fringe.
But we're going to do Sibiu first.
So we expand that.
And now, we've got this Fringe that
has a bunch of stuff on it.
It's got some crazy stuff, like
going back to a Arad.
We probably shouldn't do that.
But the thing on the entire Fringe
that's closest is Fagaras.
Because it makes immediate progress.
However, the right answer, through
the low road, is not yet cheaper.
Because it gets there kind
of in more steps.
And it doesn't look cheaper, yet.
So what do we do in Greedy Search?
We go through Fagaras.
Now, the problem is, once we
go through Fagaras, now
we can see the goal.
We can see Bucharest.
We're going to go straight there.
And this good path that would actually
have been cheap, had we kind of
checked it out.
It didn't look good right away.
And it's still on the Fringe.
We would eventually come back to
it, if it were the only path.
But we end up picking the high road.
And therefore, we drive farther.
So what can go wrong
with Greedy Search?
Well, what can go wrong is you don't
get the thing you wanted.
You end up with some kind of goal.
But it's not the cheapest.
All right.
So how does Greedy Search work?
Well, all I have to really do
is tell you the strategy.
And you've got the algorithm.
I don't need to go through
Tree Search again.
The strategy is expand a
goal, that you think is
closest to the goal state.
Which means, in code, you take the
state that node corresponds to.
You execute the heuristic on it. the
heuristic is in general code, not a
Lookup Table.
You execute the heuristic.
You take the number.
And that's your priority.
The thing with the lowest number,
at any given time, comes off.
Unlike Uniform Cost, which looked
at cumulative costs, this
is a one-shot number.
You don't add up your heuristics.
And you always go kind of towards
whatever appears to be
closest to the goal.
Now, a common case is that this kind of
Best-First, Greedy Search will take
you straight to a goal.
But it will be the wrong one.
So I have this image in my head
here, where you go straight
down into the tree.
And in general, unlike Depth First
Search, where you go straight off into
some crazy left-door way, you're going
straight in some basically reasonable
way, especially if your heuristic
is really good.
And so you get to a goal.
But it may not be the right goal.
So it's deep like Depth
First Research.
But it's not kind of completely rogue,
like Depth First Search.
Now, on the other hand, you're heuristic
could play games with you.
It could tell you that everything is
close to the goal, except the things
that are actually close to the goal.
And then what happens?
Well, then you go on this goose chase.
And you expand the entire tree,
except the part you want.
So really, Greedy is only as
good as your heuristic.
And in general, heuristics
aren't perfect.
And this thing on the bottom
doesn't always happen.
But it certainly can, if your
heuristic isn't very good.
You can think of Greedy, basically, as
having all the properties of Depth
First Search.
Except that Depth First
Search is guided.
And it's maybe guided well.
So let's look at what this
looks like in execution.
Sometimes, it looks great.
So if I look at the empty water--
remember how Uniform Cost Search
checked every direction?
What does Greedy do?
AUDIENCE: When it works, it works.
PROFESSOR: When it works
it works, right.
How about--
what does Greedy Search do
in the case of that maze?
Well, here you can see what it did.
It's actually pretty interesting.
It expanded, unsurprisingly, things
that seemed to make progress.
And then, at that point, going
left seem to make progress.
So it expanded all of this.
Then, it couldn't get any closer.
The things that looked closest were
actually kind of curling back.
So it expanded these next.
Those did not work.
Rather than declaring failure--
it's not a local search.
This other stuff was still
on the fringe.
And so it did eventually come back
and expand all that stuff.
Now, what's the problem?
The problem is, well, it avoided the
worst possible outcome, which is just
not even finding a solution.
It did know to backtrack, in some sense,
meaning take things off the
fringe and try again.
But in fact, the optimal solution goes
right here and then straight down.
The problem with Greedy here is, the
right solution actually goes
backwards, according to the
heuristic, very briefly,
before it can make progress.
Greedy is not OK with that.